[Dave] Welcome back for Unit 2!
欢迎来到第二单元!
I hope everyone is getting confidence in the things you learned in unit 1.
我希望各位对第一单元所学的知识有信心
We're going to continue to build on those in this unit as well as in rest of the course.
在这一单元及课程的其余部分 我们将要继续学习计算机科学知识
Our main goal for this unit is to make the web crawler, instead of just finding one link in the page,
本单元的我们的主要目标是建立网络爬虫 不仅仅是在页面 (page) 里找一个链接 (link)
to find all the links on a page,
而是找到页面里的所有链接 (links)
so that we can follow these links and collect more and more pages on the web.
所以我们可以跟随这些链接 (links) 在网络上收集到更多的页面 (pages)
To do that we need two big new concepts in computer science.
为了做这些 我们需要学习计算机科学中的两个新的重要概念
The first is procedures. Procedures are a way to package code so that we can reuse it more easily.
第一个是过程 (procedures) 它是封装代码的方法 使得我们可以更容易地再次使用它
The second is control. We need a way to be able to make decisions, and to do repetition, to find all those links on a page.
第二个是控制 (control) 我们需要一种方法去做决定、做重复的事情 去寻找页面上所有的链接 (links)
What we saw at the end of Unit 1 was a way to extract the first URL from a web page--
在第一单元结尾中我们所学到的是一种提取第一个 URL 的方法
that's great--we could find the first target.
那非常好 我们可以找到第一个目标了
But if we want to build a good crawler,
但是如果我们想要创建一个好点的爬虫
we don't just care about the first one,
我们不能仅仅只关心第一个链接 (link)
we care about all of the links on the page.
我们应该关心到页面上所有的链接 (links)
We need to extract all of those links--
我们需要提取所有的链接 (links)
figure out where all of those links point to--
找出这些链接 (links) 指向何处
so we'll find many more pages to crawl than just the first one.
这样我们就可以找到更多页面去爬 而不只是第一个
So, that's the goal for this class as far as building a web browser.
就建立网络浏览器而言 这就是我们这门课的目标
To do that, we're going to learn two really big ideas in computer science.
为了达成目标 我们将要学习在计算机科学中的两个很重要的概念
The first is about procedures,
第一个是过程 (procedure)
and that's a way to package up code so we can use it
一种封装代码的方法 我们可以比以往更有效的
in a much more useful way than we could before.
进行使用它
The second is about control.
第二个是控制 (control)
Control structures will give us a way to keep going
控制结构 (control structures) 将会给我们一个方法去持续
to find all the links on a page.
找到页面上所有的连接 (links)
So, let's remember the code we had at the end of Unit 1.
所以 我们来回想一下第一单元所学习的代码
We solved this problem of extracting the first URL from the page--
我们解决了提取页面上第一个 URL 的问题
we assumed the page was initialized to the contents of some web page.
我们假设页面被初始化为一些网页的内容
We initialized the variable "start_link"
我们把变量 "start_link" 初始化为
to the result of invoking "find" on "page,"
调用 page.find 的结果
passing in the start of the link tag.
传入链接标签 (link tag) 的起点
Then, we initialized the variable "start_quote"
然后 把变量 "start_quote" 初始化为
to the result of finding, in the page,
调用 page.find 的结果
the first quote following that link tag.
链接标签 (link tag) 后的第一个引号
Then, we initialized the variable "end_quote"
然后我们初始化变量 "end_quote"
to the result of invoking "find" on "page,"
为调用 page.find 的结果
to find the first quote following the start quote.
去找到 "start_quote" 后的第一个引号
And, then, we assigned to the variable "url"--
然后 我们赋值变量 "url"
extracting from the page--
它提取自页面
from the character after the "start_quote,"
从 "start_quote" 后的字母
to the character just before the "end_quote,"
到 "end_quote" 之前的字母
we could print out that URL.
我们可以打印出 URL
This worked to find the first URL on the page.
这样就能找出页面上的第一个 URL
If we wanted to find the second one,
如果我们想找到第二个 URL
we could do it all again.
我们可以将上述过程再做一遍
We could say, now we want to advance
现在我们想更进一步
so we're only looking at the rest of the page.
所以我们只看页面的剩余部分
We could do that by updating the variable "page,"
我们可以通过更新变量 "page"
assigning to it the result of the rest of the page, starting from "end_quote"--
从 "end_quote" 赋值到页面剩余的结果
and, remember, when there's a blank after the colon
记住 当冒号后有空白时
that means select from this position, to the very end--
就意味着从这个位置一直到最后
and then we can do all the same stuff.
我们可以再把以上过程再做一次
We'll do "start_link" again; ...
我们再做一次 "start_link" …
we'll do "start_quote" again; ...
我们再做一次 "start_quote" …
Now we've got code that's going to print out the first URL--
现在我们有了打印出第一个 URL 的代码
keep going, updating the variable "page"--
继续 更新变量 "page"
and then doing the exact same thing--
然后重复上述过程
printing out the second URL.
打印出第二个 URL
If we wanted to print out the first three,
如果我们想要打印出前三个 URL
we could do it again...
我们可以再来一次…
So now, we've got code to print out the first three
现在我们有打印出页面上
URL's on the page--
前三个 URL 的代码
let's scroll all the way up--so you've got--
让我们向上滑动 你有打印出第一个 URL
print out the first one--keep going--
继续下去
print out the second one--keep going--
打印出第二个 URL 继续下去
so this can go on forever.
这样这个过程就可以无限继续下去
The reason we have computers
我们为什么发明计算机
is to save humans from doing lots of tedious work.
就是节省人力 避免做很多乏味的工作
We don't want to make humans do lots of tedious work--
我们并不像人们做很多乏味的工作
certainly, typing this out, over and over again,
当然 一遍又一遍的打字
would be really tedious,
会是很枯燥无味的
and it wouldn't really even work that well.
甚至做的并不会很好
We have pages with hundreds of links,
有些页面有数以百计的链接 (links)
but there are other pages with only one or two links.
但是有的页面只有一个或两个链接 (links)
So, it wouldn't make sense to copy this hundreds of times.
所以将这些复制上百遍是没有意义的
There's always going to be some web page that has more links
总有些网页有比我们的复制的程序
than we have copies of it--
有更多的链接数
and any page that has fewer copies, we're going to run into problems
同时 有些页面比我们的程序数量更少 会给我们带来问题
because we're not going to be finding any of those links.
因为我们不会去找这些链接 (links)
So, our goal today is to solve all of those problems.
所以我们今天的目标便是解决这些问题